# 切开之后
After you cut it open
# 一看就能看出来
you can tell by just looking at it
# 入味没入味
whether the flavour is there or not
# 大爷这好吃
It's good Da Ye.
# 您来吧 您来您来
Take a bite!
# 筋 长筋 您长长筋骨
The tendon's quite good, have some!
(you are what you eat)
# 今天咱们来个酱牛肉
We are making braised beef today
# 你看网友为什么想你啊
Our viewers miss you pal, why?
# 来了就是高大上
You make fancy food!
# 除了羊肉就是牛肉
Lamb, beef, you got it all, feasty!
# 人家说小亮净做横货
Viewers comment that "Xiao Liang only makes meat."
# 肉买回来先洗先泡
We soak the meat first
# 泡完了之后开刀
once soaked, cut it
# 开刀给它开成三条
into three strips
# 这是前腿腱子
This is front shank
# 条打的差不多三指宽的条
Cut into strips, around the same width as three fingers
# 入味的刀口要给它留出来
Make some incisions for marination
# 开完刀之后
After that, we put some soy sauce as base
# 咱们先来一点酱油底口
# 就是黄豆酱油
Regular soy sauce would just do
# 然后随后就是玉桂粉
A bit cinnamon powder
# 咱们肉是有三斤差不多
We have around 1.5 kilos of meat (~3lbs)
# 一斤您就放两克就行
Around 4g per kilo
# 给它拌匀了
Rub it in
# 您用干黄酱也行
Soy bean paste, whether dry or wet, would do
# 稀黄酱也行
# 一斤肉您就一两酱就够了
Use about 100g marinade for every kilo of meat
# 把这酱给它均匀的裹上
Rub the marinade evenly
# 搁冰箱里腌制
and let it marinade in fridge
# 我还得来点盐
I need to add more salt
# 咱为了让它快速吃
to make the flavour penetrate more quickly
# 得3勺
About three tsp,
# 这样拌匀了
Mix it well
# 吃酱牛肉家里边要是费
If you make braised beef often
# 您就提前腌
You can marinade it in advance, for up to 48 hours
# 最多我试过能腌到48小时
# 这刀口一定要冲下
Place the cut-side down, the tendons up
# 外面筋皮朝上
# 这个就腌着它就行了
Marinade it for at least 24 hours in fridge
# 搁冰箱里边24小时
# 您就可以用了
then you can use it
# 这就是我提前腌好的
This is what I have marinaded
# 你看这颜色不是鲜红了
You see, the colour changed from bright to darker red.
# 有点酱红色
# 它会把酱吃进去
The marinade is absorbed into the meat
# 还有特别挺实
The meat also turned firmer
# 下一步清洗
Next, wash the marinade off the meat
# 因为咱们酱还有料粉咱们不能要
because we don't need the marinade sauce
# 咱要的是它的味道
We just need its flavour.
# 洗干净了 这就齐了
Right, clean, all set
# 咱们今天这个是做牛肉的
The spice mix will be published on his channel
# 这个料的配比在冯肉肉小号上
# 它有一个精确的比例
It's a precise ratio to be referenced
# 大家可以照着去抓料包去
# 主料白芷
Main spice: Baizhi
# 白芷的辅料是白蔻和小茴香
Accompanying by white cardamom and fennel seeds
# 它们3个的辅料是花椒和大料
And Sichuan peppercorn and star anise
# 它们5个的辅料是香叶
Partnered also with bay leaves
# 就行了 就这六味料就够了
That's it, 6 spices
# 搭配的非常的合理
That combination makes total sense to me.
# 这个料咱们给它泡一会
We soak and wash it a bit
# 然后清洗一下
# 这牛肉咱们温水下锅
Place the beef in warm water
# 它放进去之后不变色
You can tell the water temp is right
# 这水温下去就行
when the beef doesn't change colour when put in
# 我盖上盖
close the lid
# 咱们腌完之后
There won't be as much scum after marination
# 它不会出这么多大血沫
# 稍微一撇就行
Just remove them
# 煮10分钟到20分钟
Boil 10 to 20 minutes
# 这个沫您给它撇干净了
Remove all the impurities
# 咱们搁这边煮着
Let it simmer on the side
# 咱们家里边
If you don't like beefy flavour, discard the broth
# 你要是不喜欢吃牛肉味特别重
# 这汤倒掉
If you don't like beefy flavour, discard the broth
# 重新沏汤
Start with a new pot of water to boil
# 你要是喜欢原汁的
Otherwise, keep the broth
# 就用这个汤不用倒
# 把这个沫打干净了就行了
Just remove all the impurities
# 炒酱
Stir fry the sauce
# 油您稍微宽一点
A bit more oil
# 葱一定要跟酱画等号
Important: use the same amount of leek as the sauce
# 咱们来点葱姜
Leek and ginger
# 咱们今天用的是色拉油
We're using normal cooking oil,
# 这个油您可以使什么呀
but you can be creative here,
# 上市场您买点黄油老鸡的鸡油
For example you can use chicken fat
# 买回来给它炼了
render it to chicken oil at home
# 炼完了之后
You can use that oil
# 用这油来炒酱是最好的
It'd be even better that way
# 这葱姜的香味一出来
Cook out the leek and genger flavours
# 就可以加料
And then add in the spices
# 这个料也不要炸的过于火大
Don't fry the spices on high heat
# 就是小火
Use low heat
# 这是咱们刚才腌制的酱
This is the marinade we've used
# 这也是稀黄酱
It's a looser soy bean paste
# 4两酱
About 200grams in there
# 酱下锅进行炒制
In to the wok
# 它把这油一吃进去
Once the oil is absorbed, we add in the broth
# 咱们就可以往里边添汤
# 齐活
There
# 把肉捞出来
Get the meat out
# 咱们炒的这个料
The stir fried soup base is ready then
# 现在这个酱就可以了
# 就是往这里边一倒
Pour it there and boil it for 15-20 minutes
# 您给它熬个15分钟到20分钟
# 把这料味还有
Cook out the sauce and spice flavour
# 葱姜的香味给熬出来
# 这个料待会咱是需要打出来的
We strain out the spice mix later
# 打出来之后搁冰箱里边
After that, leave it in the fridge
# 冷冻冰箱给它冻上
Freeze it
# 您下次还可以酱两次
you can use it twice more later
# 用这个料包
Use this
# 咱们这煮了有20分钟了
We have boiled it for 20 minutes already
# 你要不喜欢香料味重
If you don't like the spice flavours to be too strong
# 您就少煮10分钟
boil it for 10 minutes less
# 你要喜欢这个料味
If you like the spice flavours
# 您就多煮10分钟
boil it for 10 minutes more
# 就是连酱渣带香料全要打出来
Strain everything out
# 这个别给扔了
Don't just dump them
# 下回再酱的时候
Next time you make this dish
# 还可以放进去
you can reuse this.
# 这个还可以卤两回
IT's good for two more times
# 汤呢 我先得调味
Flavour the soup base here
# 搁几个小辣椒
A few chilis
# 您可搁可不搁
Totally up to you
# 这是根据您自己的口味
Based on your own taste
# 搁几块冰糖
Some rock sugars
# 因为这酱还有料
We need sugar because the sauce and spices
# 它煮完了之后它会回苦
it has a bitter aftertaste once you boil it
# 冰糖是调味的
We balance that out using sugar.
# 有个十几块就够了
Just tens of them would be enough.
# 牛肉
Beef,
# 搁到锅里
Place the beef in the pot
# 汤呢 酱渣和料渣给它篦出来
straining out everything else
# 齐活
Done
# 现在咱们高压锅（压上）
Now let's use pressure cooker (to cook)
# 开始（36分钟）
Let's start (cook for 36 minutes)
# 该出锅了
'Bout time, let's take it out
# 该出锅了 到点了
# 半天了 这家伙
It's been a long time, buddy.
# 嚯
Heh
# 真红啊
Nice red colour in there
# 端出来
Take it out
# 颜色它要是淡
If the colour is too light (not as red as you like)
# 您还可以搁在锅里边
you can put it back to the pot
# 给它收收汤
reduce the broth a bit
# 加一点酱油或者老抽调一下色
Add in some regular or dark soy sauce for the colour
# 大火顶到头
High heat
# 老抽
Dark soy sauce
# 这个颜色自己掌握
You are after all the controller of the beef colour
# 您喜欢重色
A bit more soy sauce if you like the darker colour
# 您就多来一点 多来一点没事
A bit more , no problem
# 听师父的
Listen to the master!
# 色上来了吧 一煮就上色
You see, the colour is coating the meet, once boils
# 尝一下汤口应该是没问题
The soup is right on
# 因为这样做了无数回了
Done this a million times already
# 这么多肉
Lots of meat
# 没问题就是这味
No problem, this is the right flavour!
# 好嘞 出锅了
Sure, take it out
# 瞧瞧这亮
See, how shinny is the meat
# 齐活
All done
# 看咱们切开之后
It's clear whether the flavour is there after cut open
# 一看就能看出来入味没入味
# 肯定是透了 是腌透了
You see the marinade penetrated perfectly, Da Ye
# 你看 透了 大爷你看
# 来一块
Take one!
# 这么大块哪受得了啊
It's too big lol
# 咱这个最好是第二天
It's best to wait till next day,
# 搁冰箱里边
rest in fridge
# 给它用保鲜膜封好了
sealed well with plastic film
# 第二天吃更香
It's better on the second day
# 现在就挺香的的
It's already good now
# 现在挺香
# 大爷这好吃
It's good, Da Ye
# 您来 您来
Come on come on
# 筋 长筋   长点筋骨
Take some tendon
# 长点筋骨
It's good for you
# 小亮给你来一口
Xiao Liang, have a bit too
# 您来这个 我来这块瘦的
You can have this, I will take this lean one
# 你长长筋
Help you grow some tendon
# 我长点肉 长点肌肉
I grow some muscle
# 入味入的特别
The flavour is there
# 然后好多牛肉
Many beef dishes are bland inside
# 炖出来里边没味
# 它里外是一致的
Yours is perfect, in and out
# 吃完了不塞牙
It will not stuck in between your teeth.
# 火候必须得拿捏的非常好
Good job managing the heat!